<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Alex&#39; Blog</title>
    <link>https://dfghj.de/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Alex&#39; Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 04:16:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dfghj.de/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Run Jupyter Notebooks as a Service on macOS</title>
      <link>https://dfghj.de/run-jupyter-notebooks-as-a-service-on-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 04:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dfghj.de/run-jupyter-notebooks-as-a-service-on-macos/</guid>
      <description>I was looking for a way to run jupyer notebook without using a constantly open terminal or a screen session. On macOS there is a way to create services using a .plist file and the launchctl command.
Because I use different environments for all Python related stuff, it wasn’t immediately clear to me how to do this when I’ve installed Jupyter only in a pyenv. After some fiddling around, I finally solved it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show Download and Upload speed on your LaMetric Time</title>
      <link>https://dfghj.de/show-download-and-upload-speed-on-your-lametric-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 13:13:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dfghj.de/show-download-and-upload-speed-on-your-lametric-time/</guid>
      <description>Following a request at the LaMetric forum I wrote a small Python script for displaying your current download and upload speed on a LaMetric Time. The script can run on your own laptop or server (preferred).
Basically you need to do two things:
Create an app for the LaMetric Time run the script that performs the speed test and push the results to the device 1. Create an indicator app This is quite an easy thing to do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LaMetric Firmware 1.7.5</title>
      <link>https://dfghj.de/lametric-firmware-1-7-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 22:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dfghj.de/lametric-firmware-1-7-5/</guid>
      <description>A new firmware for the LaMetric Time is out – version 1.7.5 has some nice things to offer for those of us who would like to use the device in home automation (sadly the documentation is not yet updated). While this has been announced in the change log for 1.7.4, there have been some bugs and there are still one or two things that needs fixing, but that’s just minor stuff.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
